JORGE ROMAN

SOFTWARE & NETWORK ENGINEER

Network | Content Developer | Cisco Knowledge

I am a Tech Engineer Level 2/3

I am also, a Content Developer and I work in Front End, also I have been working in HMTL Email Development (from the scratch and responsive), besides that, I have been working in layouts for Bootstrap. Work with CMS's like AEM (basic to MID), WP and Joomla, including the most popular web frameworks and Content Management Systems. QA Engineer (Manual and Automation) with strong knowledge Design, Web Design and programming skills with + 1 year software development experience emphasing mostly in Content Development and Front End Software Architecture. One to two years working experience at Upwork

Contact information

Phones: +506 2236 6483 | +506 8652 6183

Email: romansmartgeek5@gmail.com | jorgeromanctibas@hotmail.com

Skype: jorgeromanctibas@hotmail.com

Physical Address: San Jose

EDUCATION

2015 – 2022 System Engineering Ulacit

LANGUAGES

Spanish: Native **English:** Advanced C2 **Other Language:** Basic Portuguese

TECHNICAL SKILLS

		Platforms			
Windows 7,8.1,10	Windows Server 2003 – 2016	Linux (INCECOM Diploma) Linux – EDx Diploma Debian Red Hat Suse Ubuntu Centos Patching	Unix	SUN Solaris	MSCE
AWS	Clouding Azure PAAS SAAS	O365 (Outlook, Microsoft Dynamics)	Hyper-V	VMWare Virtualization	VOIP
MAC	CISCO CCNA	CISCO CCNA Security	cpanel	WFH	Kali Linux

PALO ALTO OS – Juniper CISSP Foundation (Cibrary) HTML5 – CSS3 – Oracle Firewalls Javascript (Coursera Diploma)	e VM AIX					
HUX HPUX IBM - Introduction to IBM IBM - HP Cybersecurity Tools & Cyber Cybersecurity (OS Attacks - Coursera Analyst Professional Certificate - O 2021 - Coursera						
Front End: Frameworks and Content Management System and Other Technologies						
Bootstrap Email Templates CSS, CCS3 Docker Drug	pal Joomla					
Boostrap Sitefinite CMS Umbraco CMS HTML HTML5 Mage Materialize	ento Wordpress					
Microsoft Teams Marketo Litmus Javascript (Basic) Jquery ((Basic) PHP (Basic)					
Agile ITIL Scrum Git (Github) Eclip	ose Visual Studio Code					
Diseño Gráfico Log me In Go2Meeting TeamViewer Zoo	om Marketing & Sales					
Business Adm Comptia + CRM Slack SCC PHP for WordPress	CM Salesforce					
Precompilers						
Jekyll Handlebars PUG SASS LES	SS .Net					
Databases						
Access MySQL MongoDB Oracle (Basic) Powe	er BI Microstrategy					
Tableau .Net Web Services Reporting Orac Services	cle Web Form					
QA Engineering tools						
Cypress JasmineJS Jenkins KarmaJS Katalon	,					
q Test Ranorex Selenium TestComplete TestF	Rail UFT/QTP					
XRay Zephyr						
Soft Skills						

I have learned latest skills like Critical Thinking and Teamwork. Also I am enthusiastic and keen on the new state-of-the-art technologies doing Multitasking and being Proactive getting Adaptability and Attention to Detail, taking Ownership and Leadership on all company procedures in the IT area and Software

Always eager to learn full understanding of coding cycle, data structure; web, design and programming architecture. I think that clear communication and Integrity is the key for a successful team and career development

WORK EXPERIENCE

QUALFON | Technology Company | Heredia

Role: Engineer Level 2

• Lytx Tech Support Level 2 – (January 2022 – Current day) Tshoot of different devices and tools related to Lytx

INFOTREE | Procter & Gamble [Massive Comsuption Product Company] | San Jose

Role: Automation Engineer

• **DDT Engineer** – (February 2020 – February 2021) Temporary Contract for one year Automation of processes and workflows (using Advanced Excel, Power Bl, Knime, SAP, Databricks, Citrix, Citrix Receiver, etc)

Testing and troubleshooting of QA automation Macros and jobs

• Business Processes Documentation

Documentation of processes and workflows of different categories

TEK XPERTS | [Clouding and Software Technology Company] | San Pedro

Microsoft Azure Engineer - Intermediate Level, (Aug 2019 - November 2019, Temporary Contract)

Role: Engineer Level 2

- Azure AD, clouding and virtualization issues
- Troubleshooting Config & Perf PAAS issues being in contact with other departments: SAAS & DevOps
- Creation of VMs and VNets (Deployments) Virtual Box, Citrix, VMWare, HPUX, Xen, etc
- VNet-to-VNet VPN connections (VPN Gateway's peering) Site to Site and Point to Site
- VPN subnet connections
- Adding Memory and Storage to the different VMs
- Layer 1/2/3, FC
- Testing and troubleshooting of QA automation jobs

CSS Corp | VOIP Internet Technology Company | Heredia

Cisco VOIP Tier 2 – Tech Support Agent, (Feb 2018 – Sept 2018)

Role: Service Desk Engineer

- Troubleshooting of physical devices (Firewalls, Routers, Switches, APs): Mostly Palo Alto Networks & Cisco Meraki –
 Barracuda Fortinet ZyXEL ZyWALL USG o SonicWall others
- AIX, HP, HUX, IBM, Cisco, Dell, Linux flavors, Windows, MAC computers, etc for different kind of support for customers in the US
- Layer 1/2/3, FC
- Apps Installation and Billing issues
- Creation of VMs, PBX and branches

Major contribution to the team and goals achieved: 98.54% QA

MENTORSHIP/SCHOLARSHIP

ABBOTT | Medical Company | Alajuela

Role: Network Admin Engineer / Sys Admin

• **DDT Engineer** – (2015) 3 training months (pasantía)

REFERENCES

Delinquency Sheet (from OIJ)

Dave Perez | GAP | Front End Engineer | 8318 2455 Diego Chinchilla Chinchilla | Licenciado en Inglés, Maestría en Historia | Cootepecos | 6099 8828 Andrey Cordero Madriz | Licenciado en Administración | Banco Popular | 8644 6687

Documents and diplomas will be issued upon request